# Matteo Bertrone

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER · RESEARCH ASSISTANT AT POLYTECHNIC OF TURIN

24, Corso Duca degli Abruzzi, Turin, Italy 10129

🛘 (+39) 334 798-6923 | 🗷 m.bertrone@gmail.com | 😭 mbertrone.github.io | 🖸 mbertrone | 🛅 bertrone

"Everyone thinks of changing the world, but no one thinks of changing himself" - Leo Tolstoy



# Summary\_

I'm research assistant at Department of Control and Computer Engineering of Polytechnic of Turin, Italy, where I'm working on network programmability, SDN and could computing, eXpress Data Path (XDP) and eBPF. I deal with distributed programming, APIs design, concurrency, and performance optimization. I love to code, but I also love to share ideas and feedback with my team, not only technical ones.

# Work Experience\_

## **Polytechnic of Turin**

Turin, Italy

RESEARCH FELLOW & SOFTWARE ENGINEER (C++, EBPF, Go)

- Core developer of Polycube, an eBPF-based framework for networking.
- Implemented and designed a system daemon, exposing REST API, able to deploy services, configure them, show current configuration and status, create virtual topologies, and connect them to Dockers, namespaces, VMs, NICs. Implemented a CLI to interact with the daemon.
- $\bullet \ \ \text{Developed services (bridge, router, load balancer, nat), exploiting eBPF to be loaded and optimized at runtime, without modifying Linux kernel.}$
- Designed and developed a clone of iptables firewall, exploiting efficient algorithms and XDP optimizations, leading up to 10x performance gain.

#### **Huawei Technologies**

Santa Clara, CA, U.S.A.

INTERN (C++, EBPF, Go)

• Developed Polycube framework and services. Architected natting module and improved design of iptables clone.

#### Nebbiolo Technologies, INC. (Start-up company)

Milpitas, CA, U.S.A. Feb. 2017 - May. 2017

May. 2018 - Jun. 2018

CONSULTANT (C++, EBPF, Go)

• Designed and deployed a lightweight bridging networking solution, as a substitute of Linux bridge.

#### PLUMgrid INC. (Acquired by VMware)

Santa Clara, CA, U.S.A.

INTERN (EBPF, Go)

• Developed a networking provider for OpenStack. Increased visibility by publishing it under iovisor community repository.

EISWORLD Turin, Italy

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER (C#)

Mar. 2014 - May. 2014

Sep. 2016 - Jan. 2017

• Developed a network analysis and diagnostic tool for Fiat Chrysler Automobiles, used to debug and detect issues on dealers network.

# Projects & Open Source\_\_\_\_\_

#### **PolyCube**

CORE DEVELOPER - POLYCUBE IS AN OPEN SOURCE FRAMEWORK TO BUILD VIRTUAL NETWORK FUNCTIONS WITH XDP AND EBPF

## lovisor-ovn

MAIN DEVELOPER - IOVISOR-OVN PROVIDES AN EFFICIENT DATA PLANE REPLACEMENT FOR OPENSTACK NETWORKING.

github.com/polycube-network

Jan. 2017 - PRESENT

github.com/iovisor/iovisor-ovn

Sep. 2016 - Jan. 2017

# Publications \_\_\_\_

## **Accelerating Linux Security with eBPF iptables**

ACM SIGCOMM 2018 Conference Posters and Demos

#### Toward an eBPF-based clone of iptables

NETDEV 0X12, THE TECHNICAL CONFERENCE ON LINUX NETWORKING

## Creating Complex Network Services with eBPF: Experience and Lessons Learned

IEEE INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON HIGH PERFORMANCE SWITCHING AND ROUTING

Budapest, Hungary

20-25 August 2018

Montréal, Canada

11-13 July 2018

Bucharest, Romania

17-20 June 2018

## Presentation \_\_

#### **Open vSwitch Fall Conference**

Demo - Coupling the Flexibility of OVN with the Efficiency of IOVisor: Architecture and Demo

San Jose, CA, U.S.A.

Nov. 2016

# **Education**

#### Polytechnic of Turin

MASTER'S DEGREE, COMPUTER ENGINEERING, 110/110

**Polytechnic of Turin** 

BSC Degree, Computer Engineering, 110/110

211 303C, C/1, 0.3./

Turin, Italy

2014 - 2016

Turin, Italy

2011 - 2014

JANUARY 11, 2019 MATTEO BERTRONE · RÉSUMÉ